Overleaf Privacy Notice
-----------------------

Last Modified: 11 June 2026

This Notice applies to the websites at [www.overleaf.com](https://www.overleaf.com/) or [www.sharelatex.com](https://www.sharelatex.com/) and related services (“Overleaf”).

Overleaf is operated and controlled by Digital Science UK Ltd (formerly Writelatex Ltd), with registered offices at 6 Briset Street, London, United Kingdom, EC1M 5NR or its affiliate, Digital Science & Research Solutions Inc. in the case of sales-related resources and as may be specified (“Digital Science” or “we”). We respect your concerns about privacy and value our relationship with you. This Notice explains what personal data we collect, how we may use and manage it and the rights you may have in relation to such personal data. When we refer to “personal data” in this Notice, we mean information relating to an identified or identifiable individual that we collect and use in connection with Overleaf; not aggregate or other anonymised data or information we process on behalf of our customers.

### How do we collect and use personal data?

We collect personal data in the following ways:

*   **information you provide to us directly online.** For example, when you register to use Overleaf, complete one of our web forms, subscribe to updates or make a support request, we collect the personal data you provide, like your name, email address and other basic contact details / professional information. We will use this information to enable you to access and use Overleaf or fulfil the request you've made and to track and improve the quality of the services we provide, which may involve asking you about your experience with Overleaf. You may also provide us with additional information to access and use particular features within Overleaf, such as to populate your profile, which you may update within your account settings. More occasional examples could include where you respond to a survey, complete a support request or enter into a competition.
*   **information we collect from your use of Overleaf.** When you use Overleaf, we may collect information about that usage and other technical information, such as your IP address, browser type and any referring website addresses. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you and use it to keep a record of our interaction and to enable us to support, personalize and improve Overleaf. We may also collect this type of information using cookies and other similar technologies and in some cases, cookies may be set to personalize the content and ads you receive, including on other sites - please see the cookie policy on the relevant site for further details. Where these cookies are controlled by third parties, the owner may be able to identify you based on your device or other online activity, and their use of this data is subject to their own privacy notices — please see our [cookie policy](https://www.overleaf.com/legal#Cookies) for further details.
*   **information you provide to us in person.** For example, when you visit one of our exhibition booths or attend one of our events, you may provide us with your contact details. We will use this information to answer your enquiries or provide other information requested by you.
*   **information we collect from our other interactions / business dealings.** For example, if you attend a webinar, contact us via social media or otherwise interact with our business, including as a representative of a current / prospective customer, supplier or business partner, we may track and make a record of those interactions, which may contain personal data. If you visit one of our offices, this may be captured on CCTV and used for security reasons; and photographs / videos may be taken at our events and used for promotional purposes, details of which will be available on request at the relevant site.
*   **information provided to us by other Overleaf users.** We may receive personal data (for example, your email address) from other Overleaf users or customers, for example if they have tried to share something with you or tried to refer Overleaf to you.
*   **information we collect from third parties or publicly available sources.** We may collect information you post online (e.g. social media) about us, our products/services and/or our industry (including our competitors), for market research and product improvement purposes.

In all the above cases, where we have a relationship with you, we may also use the personal data we collect to manage and keep a record of that relationship and other business administration purposes you’d reasonably expect and, subject always to your preferences, to provide information we think may be of interest to you.

In many of the above cases, we may also use the information collected to create aggregate or other non-personal data to enable us to benchmark and improve Overleaf and for other analytical / research purposes.

Unless we specifically request it, you should not provide us with any sensitive personal information. If you provide personal data to us about someone else (such as one of your colleagues), please ensure that you have their permission to do so and that they’re aware of the contents of this Notice.

### The legal basis for our use of your personal data

In order to comply with European data privacy laws, we are required to set out the legal bases for our use of your personal data, which are as follows:

*   where you have given us your explicit consent, which you can withdraw at any time. For example, we rely on your consent to fulfill specific requests you’ve made, such as to receive our blog emails, or provide information you’ve opted-in to receive;
*   where the processing is necessary for the performance of our contract with you, or to enter into such a contract. For example, if you register to use Overleaf, we will need to use your details to set-up and administer your account;
*   where the processing is necessary to comply with our legal obligations; or
*   the processing is in our legitimate interests, provided these are not overridden by your individual rights. For example, we rely on our legitimate interests:
    *   to retain personal data that’s associated with content you’ve made public, so that personal information, associated with that content can be preserved.
    *   to verify your identity and research affiliation.
    *   to contact you when you’ve not previously given us your consent to do so, such as to tell you about things that we think might be of interest to you, or to ask for your feedback or opinion on us or our products/services.
    *   to collect publicly available information, such as posts on social media, for market research and product improvement purposes.
    *   to use CCTV on our premises for security reasons.
    *   to combine the account, usage or other personal data we have collected in connection with Overleaf with data collected in connection with other Digital Science products to enable us to deliver an improved and more integrated overall service.
    *   to track usage and create aggregated or other non-personal data from your personal data.

### Who we share your personal data with

We may share your personal data within our corporate group on a confidential basis for our internal administrative, billing and other business purposes, and to fulfill a request that you might have made. We do not generally disclose or share personal data with third parties, except where it’s necessary for legitimate business reasons, such as:

*   to the agents, advisers and service providers that assist us in running / we use to administer our business;
*   to the subcontractors and service providers\* we use to provide and support Overleaf, including, for example, providers of hosting, security and infrastructure and customer support platforms;
*   if you express interest in an initiative we’re involved in, to other participants in such initiative;
*   if Overleaf is accessed, procured or used via, used to access or procure, or synced, integrated or connected with, other products or resources, to the provider of such products or resources;
*   if you collaborate on another user’s Overleaf project, with that user and other collaborators on the project, and the respective Overleaf account owner(s);
*   if part of our business is sold to or integrated with another business, to our advisers and any prospective purchasers (and their advisers);
*   in such circumstances for which you have given your consent;
*   if necessary for the performance of the contract we have with you or in order to enforce any claims we are entitled to;
*   if required by law or ordered by a court;
*   if you register for a webinar or other event, to other attendees and co-organisers of that event;
*   in the case of your Overleaf profile, subject to your preferences (which you can change at any time, subject to limits on managed accounts), or details associated with content you’ve chosen to make public, to other users of Overleaf;
*   if someone else is paying for your account (for example, the university to which you belong) or you join a group on Overleaf, either by accepting an invitation to that group or by confirming your affiliation to that group (for example, by confirming your university email address), to administrators of that grouping (for example university staff), who may have access to information such as: your email address, profile information, and statistics on usage;
*   if you have registered using an organizational email address, to authorized representatives of that organization, so they can understand how Overleaf is being used at their organization and get in contact with you about your account (for example to make you aware of available upgrades), but limited to your email address and statistics on usage;
*   in the case of personal data you share in any Overleaf community services you participate in (for example blogs, forums, and wikis), to the public.

\*\* We include appropriate confidentiality and security obligations in our contracts with our service providers and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions (not for their own purposes). Such service providers include: Netsuite, Inc. for billing (USA), Salesforce.com, LLC for customer relationship management (USA), Qualtrics LLC (USA) for product feedback, and may also include the third parties listed [here](https://docs.overleaf.com/accounts-and-security/overleaf-data-processors).\*

Note, where you are using Overleaf pursuant to an organization’s subscription, that organization may have certain admin rights over your account, including the ability to track your usage and, in the case of managed accounts, the ability to close your account and access, delete and/or share your stuff, including by re-assigning projects; and we will act in accordance with any instructions they may give in respect of such information (if any) they may provide to us about you or which we may collect on their behalf (whose policies - not this policy - will govern how the personal data we process on their behalf is used).

### Security

We take appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data from accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss and unauthorized access, destruction, misuse, modification or disclosure, including generally accepted standards designed to protect personal data provided to us, both during transmission and once it is received. Please see our [security overview](https://www.overleaf.com/legal#Security) for details.

### Retention of your personal data

We only keep your personal data for as long as it is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or as otherwise permitted by law, after which it will be destroyed, erased or anonymised. For example, if you are an Overleaf user, we will delete your account profile if you close your account, but may however retain certain limited personal data about you to record your association with content you’ve made public, and as required to comply with applicable law.

### International transfers

While we are based in the UK, parts of our operations and much of our product infrastructure is based elsewhere, including the United States. This means that in order to run our business and operate Overleaf, personal data may be transferred to the USA, as well as to other locations where our affiliates and service providers are based. Whenever we make such transfers, we will ensure an appropriate level of protection is afforded to your personal data, which in the case of personal data originating from the UK or the European Economic Area (“EEA”) shall involve implementing at least one of the following safeguards:

*   making sure the destination country has been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data;
*   by using model form contracts that have been officially declared to afford your personal data an appropriate protection;
*   relying on an alternative recognised compliance standard for the lawful transfer of personal data.

Please email us at [privacy@overleaf.com](mailto:privacy@overleaf.com) if you would like more information about these safeguards.

### Data Privacy Framework Notice

In some cases, your subscription to use Overleaf may have been purchased via our US affiliate, Digital Science & Research Solutions Inc. (“Digital Science US”), which participates in the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework. This Notice applies to personal data transferred to Digital Science US, in the United States, from the European Economic Area and the United Kingdom, where transferred in reliance on the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework (which is referred to in this Notice as EU Personal Data).

To the extent there is any conflict between the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (“DPF Principles”) and this Notice, the DPF Principles will prevail in respect of EU Personal Data.

##### Commitment to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework Principles

Digital Science US participates in the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce its compliance with the DPF Principles regarding the processing of EU Personal Data. Digital Science US is responsible for the processing of EU and UK Personal Data, and remains liable for its onward transfer to third parties acting as agents on our behalf, in accordance with the DPF Principles.

For purposes of enforcing compliance with the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework, Digital Science US is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

To learn more about the EU-US Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework, and to view Digital Science US’s certification, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/).

##### Disclosure for national security or law enforcement

Digital Science US may be required to share your personal data with public authorities and law enforcement agencies in response to lawful requests, including requests to meet national security and law enforcement requirements.

##### Resolution of EU-US Data Privacy Framework queries and complaint mechanism

If you have an EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework and the UK Extension to the EU-US Data Privacy Framework-related (or general privacy-related) query or complaint, we encourage you to contact us (see contact details above) as a first step. Any unresolved complaints may be referred to our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). You may also contact your local supervisory authority within the European Economic Area or the United Kingdom.

Under certain conditions, more fully described in Annex I of the DPF Principles, you may invoke binding arbitration by delivering notice to us and following the procedures and subject to conditions set out in Annex I of the DPF Principles.

### Marketing

Depending on your preferences, we may contact you about things we think might be of interest to you. Some of these messages may be tailored to you, based on your interests (e.g. previous browsing activity), public profile and posts (e.g. on social media), use of our products/services, history of interactions with us, public research history and other information we may hold.

If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you can click the unsubscribe button that will be included in our emails. If you have a registered account with Overleaf, separate email preferences may also apply. Note, even if you unsubscribe from marketing messages, we may still send you emails about the services you use, such as details of new functionality / changes to legal terms of use.

### Cookies

Please see our [cookie policy](https://www.overleaf.com/legal#Cookies) for information on how we collect personal data using cookies and similar technologies.

### Your rights

Various data privacy laws give rights to individuals in respect of personal data that organisations hold about them. For example, under European data privacy laws, you may be entitled:

*   to request a copy of the personal data that we hold about you;
*   to object to the processing of your personal data; or
*   to request that your personal data is rectified or deleted, or its processing limited.

To make any requests regarding your personal data, please email us at [privacy@overleaf.com](mailto:privacy@overleaf.com). We will comply with any such requests as required in accordance with applicable law. Please be aware, however, that there are typically a number of limitations to these rights, and there may be circumstances where we’re not able to comply with your request.

##### Additional information for certain jurisdictions

For additional information relevant to certain jurisdictions about the personal data we collect, how we may use and manage it and the rights you may have in relation to such personal data, [please visit this page](https://terms.dsrsi.com/public/DigitalSciencePrivacyNotices_Supplement).

### Third party sites

If any part of Overleaf is made available on or through third party websites or other resources, includes links to such resources, or other resources contain links to any part of Overleaf, this is done for convenience only. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies of such resources as they are not subject to this Notice.

### Contact details

If you would like any further information, or have any questions or concerns, regarding your personal data, as a first step, please email us at [privacy@overleaf.com](mailto:privacy@overleaf.com) or write to us at _Digital Science UK Limited, 6 Briset Street, London, United Kingdom, EC1M 5NR, United Kingdom_.

If you are located within the EEA, you may also contact our EU representative: _DS Digital Science GmbH, Gänsheidestraße 26, 70184 Stuttgart, Germany_ (marked “FAO Overleaf GDPR Representative”).

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to your local supervisory authority for data protection issues. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns in the first instance.

### Changes to this Notice

We reserve the right to modify or replace this Notice at any time by posting the revised Notice on our website. You are responsible for reviewing and becoming familiar with any such change each time you access any part of Overleaf.
